drivetest.ca 2018-10-21

# main.nav.sercoprivacy

This privacy policy defines the processes and practices that Serco Canada Inc., the provider of driver examination (DriveTest) services for the Ministry of Transportation for Ontario (MTO), follows to ensure the security of Personal Information (PI) associated with all DriveTest customer service and communication channels, including the face-to-face, telephone and website channels. 

If you submit a comment, make an inquiry, conduct a transaction, apply for a licence, write a knowledge test, or book an appointment using this website or any other customer service channel at DriveTest (i.e., by phone, by mail, on paper, or in person), you are voluntarily supplying the information to employees of Serco Canada Inc. and MTO. Serco Canada Inc. endeavours to restrict the use of the information that you provide to only the purposes in which you intended or to satisfy your request. You will not receive any unsolicited email from Serco Canada Inc. as a result of supplying this information. Serco Canada Inc. does not rent, sell, or trade any personally identifiable information about you to third parties. 

Personal information is collected by Serco Canada Inc. on behalf of MTO under the authority of section 205 of the Highway Traffic Act. This privacy policy has been developed to comply with section 38(2) of the Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act (FIPPA) Ontario legislative requirements. Where DriveTest customer data is collected, Serco Canada Inc. makes an effort to post/publish Notice of Collection declarations. This privacy policy pertains to FIPPA and these notices of collection. 

In delivering driver examination (DriveTest) services on behalf of MTO, Serco Canada Inc. abides by all Ontario government privacy requirements. This policy aligns with and builds upon on the Privacy statement issued by the Ontario government at [https://www.ontario.ca/page/privacy-statement](https://www.ontario.ca/page/privacy-statement).

**Personal information:  **Personal information (PI) as defined under FIPPA, s.2(1) means recorded information about an identifiable individual, including, (a) information relating to the race, national or ethnic origin, colour, religion, age, sex, sexual orientation or marital or family status of the individual, (b) information relating to the education or the medical, psychiatric, psychological, criminal or employment history of the individual or information relating to financial transactions in which the individual has been involved, (c) any identifying number, symbol or other particular assigned to the individual, (d) the address, telephone number, fingerprints or blood type of the individual, (e) the personal opinions or views of the individual except where they relate to another individual, (f) correspondence sent to an institution by the individual that is implicitly or explicitly of a private or confidential nature, and replies to that correspondence that would reveal the contents of the original correspondence, (g) the views or opinions of another individual about the individual, and (h) the individual’s name where it appears with other personal information relating to the individual or where the disclosure of the name would reveal other personal information about the individual. 

**Data Subject:  **Means a person (may also be referred to as a customer or stakeholder) to whom personal data relates. 

**File:  **Means the information collected in the course of administering MTO’s driver, vehicle, and carrier programs to process, update, or change a service transaction. 

**Database:  **Means any information, including personal information that is collected by Serco to administer the Ministry’s driver, vehicle, and carrier programs, held by Serco Canada Inc. in the forms of, but not limited to, computer files, paper files, and on computer hard-drives. 

## Information Collected

## Feedback and Inquiries

When submitting a comment or making an inquiry, any data collected and entered is stored by Serco Canada Inc. and shared with MTO.

The data you provide is used only for tracking, reporting, and analyzing the quality of and volume of driver examination (DriveTest) services and to ensure an appropriate response is prepared for you.

Please note that Serco Canada Inc. has engaged Bond Brand Loyalty to process DriveTest customer satisfaction surveys. Serco and Bond use your anonymous survey results and feedback to help improve customer satisfaction.

## Driver’s Licence Applications

When you apply for a driver’s licence, Serco Canada Inc. reviews and captures personal information about you (e.g., name, address, sex, date of birth, passport number) on behalf of MTO to verify your eligibility for obtaining a licence, create temporary driver’s licence cards, and send you notices about your licence or road test. This information is entered within Serco Canada Inc. systems, encrypted, and stored within MTO databases for the purposes of maintaining your licence.

## Road Test Bookings

When booking, editing, deleting, or attending road test appointments through any customer service or communication channel, including the website:

  * You may be asked to enter your driver’s licence number and expiry date. The driver’s licence number and expiry date are used as a type of user ID and eligibility tool. When you provide this information, the appointment booking application encrypts the number and passes it securely to MTO systems to verify your driving record/history and eligibility for certain classes of licences and tests. 
  * You may be asked to provide your credit card information. Serco Canada Inc. has engaged the Desjardins Optimal Payment solution, which is managed by a Canadian financial institution, to process credit card payments associated with appointment bookings. The credit card information is not stored by Serco Canada Inc. or MTO in any way and is used only in association with your appointment booking(s). 
  * You may be asked to provide your email address or phone number. Email addresses and phone numbers are stored and used by Serco Canada Inc. and MTO to confirm road test bookings and to advise you of any changes or potential changes to your appointment. 

  * Road test evaluation sheets used at your appointment may include your name, driver’s licence number and expiry, and contact information. These scoresheets are kept at DriveTest Centres in a locked cabinet for up to 13 months so you can obtain your licence or appeal the results. The sheets are eventually shredded and discarded by authorized and security-cleared Serco Canada Inc. employees. 
  * Road test appointment refund requests are processed using your driver’s licence number. Refund requests are sent to a centralized office for processing and stored in a locked cabinet.

## DriveTest Website

## Cookies

The DriveTest website uses cookies. Cookies are small text files that may be deployed (depending on your settings) on your device when you visit our website. Cookie technology does not collect information that allows you to become personally identifiable, but it may be used to identify you as a unique but anonymous visitor to the site.

Serco Canada Inc. uses cookies to personalize your website experience. For example, cookies assist with navigation (breadcrumbs), toggling between languages, and resizing the text. Cookies may also be used to identify whether you have already been offered an opportunity to complete our customer satisfaction survey.

You can refuse to accept some or all cookies by adjusting the settings on your browser.

Please note that, if you delete all of your cookies, you might not be able to access certain parts of www.drivetest.ca and may be treated as if you have never visited the site before.

## Site Analytics

The DriveTest website uses OWA Analytics website analytics/traffic reporting software. This software may use cookies and track your IP address to help Serco Canada Inc. analyze how visitors use the site in order to optimize and streamline the website contents and features. The information captured about your use of the DriveTest website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored on servers that may reside outside of Canada. By using the website, you consent to the processing, analysis, and reporting of anonymized data about your site visit.

## Outside Links

For the convenience of www.drivetest.ca visitors, Serco Canada Inc. may provide links to third-party websites. These websites are not operated or controlled by Serco Canada Inc., and Serco Canada Inc. assumes no responsibility for the content, services, policies, cookies, or actions of these third-party sites. Serco Canada Inc. furnishes these links for your convenience, and they should be used with caution and discretion.

## Purposes of Collecting Personal Information

Personal information is collected by Serco Canada Inc. driver examination (DriveTest) services on behalf of MTO under the authority of section 205 of the Highway Traffic Act. The information is used for the administration of MTO’s driver, vehicle, and carrier programs. 

## Limiting Collection

Personal information collected is limited to the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy, and that is authorized by MTO to administer the driver, vehicle, and carrier programs. 

## Limiting Use, Disclosure, and Retention 

Collection of PI is limited to that which is necessary for the purposes collected. Serco Canada Inc. adheres to this guideline through:

  * Avoidance – do not collect data that is not required. Where possible restrict ‘free text’ fields in forms to be completed by customers; optimize the use of ‘drop down’ boxes. 
  * Using surrogate identification methods in place of unique identification data – for example, replacing drivers’ licence numbers with system-generated customer ID numbers. 

## Use of Personal Information

Personal information will be used by Serco Canada Inc. for only the purposes of administering MTO’s driver, vehicle, and carrier programs. MTO may disclose your information to authorized requestors – please see the MTO privacy policy for details.

## Transfer and Disclosure of Personal Information

Any personal information that is required to be disclosed to MTO will be encrypted and sent to those parties that have been authorized to receive.

No personal information will be disclosed through any other method unless approved by MTO in writing.

Serco Canada Inc. will respond to a request of the data subject for information relating to data held through the same medium as the original request. All reasonable efforts will be made prior to the release of information to confirm the identity of the requester and that it is the data subject. Serco Canada Inc. will provide details of all third-party disclosures of the same data subject’s PI. 

Personal information will not be disclosed to third parties without the individual's knowledge and consent.

## Retention of Personal Information

Personal information will be retained in databases as long as the file is active and for such periods of time as necessary to administer MTO’s driver, vehicle, and carrier programs and as may be prescribed by MTO and/or applicable laws and regulations.

A file is deemed inactive if the service transaction is deemed completed and/or resolved and there are no further actions necessary to administer MTO’s driver, vehicle, and carrier programs. Inactive files on databases will be purged, or shredded and securely disposed of immediately upon being deemed inactive.

## Safeguarding Personal Information

Physical, organizational, and technology measures are used to safeguard personal information to ensure only authorized employees who need to know, and require this information to conduct their duties have access.

**Organizational Safeguards:  **Access to personal information is limited to only those authorized employees that need to know this information to conduct their duties. Authorized employees are required to submit to regular background checks and sign a confidentiality agreement that binds them to maintain the confidentiality of all personal information to which they have access. 

**Physical Safeguards:** Active files are stored in secured locations when not in use. Access to work areas where active files may be in use is restricted to authorized employees only. All inactive files or personal information no longer required are shredded and securely disposed of, to prevent access by unauthorized persons. 

**Technology Safeguards:** Personal information contained in computers and electronic databases are password protected. Access to all computers is password protected. Serco Canada Inc.’s computer systems have firewall protection sufficient to protect personal and confidential information from unauthorized persons, virus attacks and "sniffer" software arising from Internet activity. No employee that has access to personal information will transfer personal information electronically to any person or party unless authorized to do so, and if authorized, only by accepted and secured electronic methods.

## Complaints

If a customer has a concern about Serco Canada Inc.’s personal information handling practices, a complaint, in writing, may be directed to the Privacy and Security Director.

Any questions, requests for access to information, or complaints should be sent to one of the addresses below:  
Serco Canada Inc.  
Privacy and Security Director  
Downsview Park  
37 Carl Hall Rd  
Toronto ON M3K 2E2  
Email: customercomments (at) drivetest (dot) ca

Upon receipt and verification of the customer’s identity, the Privacy and Security Director will investigate the complaint and provide a written report of the investigation's findings to the customer.

If the Privacy and Security Director determines that the customer’s complaint is justified, the Privacy and Security Director will take the necessary steps to correct the applicable information handling practice and/or amend the privacy policy and any applicable procedures. If the Privacy and Security Director determines that the customer’s complaint is not justified, the customer will be notified in writing.

If the customer is dissatisfied with the finding and actions taken by the Privacy and Security Director, the customer may submit a complaint to the Ontario Information and Privacy Commissioner at one of the addresses below:  
Information and Privacy Commissioner of Ontario  
2 Bloor Street East, Suite 1400  
Toronto, Ontario M4W 1A8  
Email: info (at) ipc.on.ca

## Revisions and Updates

This Privacy Policy is effective April 2016. This policy is subject to amendments in response to changes in the privacy legislation. The Privacy and Security Director will review and revise the Privacy Policy from time to time as required by changes in privacy law.
